Angelo Luca Fiore Senior Software Engineer

Orta Nova (Foggia / FG) 71045 Italy

github.com/angelo-luca

Profile

I am a Software Engineer with 15 years of experience in designing, developing, and maintaining sophisticated web and desktop applications. Throughout my extensive career in the IT industry, I have collaborated with prominent startups and rapidly growing companies. I have architected intricate services and solutions and transformed raw data into actionable insights.

Skills

```
React • Next.js • Vue.js • ASP.NET • C# • TypeScript • Node.js • Ruby on Rails • Go • Tailwind CSS • Material UI • HTML • CSS • PHP
```

Professional Experience

1996/01 – present Italy

Full Stack Developer

Freelancer

- Developed dynamic user interfaces with Next.js for real-time patient monitoring, improving the responsiveness and efficiency of care delivery.
- Increased usability and total app coverage by 20%, and improved the overall UX/UI experience of the initial platform.
- Involved in various phases of Software Development Life Cycle(SLDC) following Agile Methodology.
- Spearheaded the development of a healthcare application using Node.js and Next.js, enhancing patient data management and streamlining clinical workflows.
- Implemented secure RESTful APIs with Node.js to handle sensitive medical data, ensuring compliance with healthcare regulations like HIPAA.
- Wrote unit testing to deliver optimal browser functionality using Jest and Cypress.

2007/02 - 2008/03 Italy

Software Engineer

Afa Systems

- Led the development of a website design platform utilizing JQuery and PHP, resulting in a 30% increase in user engagement within the first two months.
- Designed and implemented scalable front-end architecture using micro-frontends, resulting in a remarkable 40% improvement in scalability.
- Developed an intuitive and visually appealing UI with complex animations using HTML, CSS and JQuery for the marketing website, resulting in a 40% increase in user engagement.
- Introduced and executed static website rendering with iframe, resulting in a 70% performance improvement, and enhanced SEO optimization.
- Engineered an intuitive RSVP management system, reducing RSVP processing time by 50% and improving user satisfaction by 20%.
- Created core API endpoints using PHP (authentication and payment processing) and refactored database schema, leading to a 20% performance boost.

2006/08 - 2007/11 Italy

Software Engineer

Next Future

- Integrated drones with the Fusion Platform, enhancing operational capabilities.
 Optimized PostgreSQL databases and implemented MYSQL databases, improving data management efficiency.
- Developed and deployed two cross platform mobile application built with React Native for freelance clients.

2002/04 - 2003/02

Italy

Frontend Developer

Informatica Discount

- Worked on static page using HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Customer care and support.
- Product Sale and management.
- Stock management.

Languages

• Italian

• English

Education

2005 - 2009

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

Italy

Istituto Tecnico Industriale S.Altamura